JAY VYAS

Skylish Avenue, Punawale, Pune +91 875-875-6225 jay.vyas1@outlook.com

It is with demonstrated experience in following Jay Vyas policy, information technology operator practices, in addition to extensive professional background in IT and Security that I am submitting my resume for this job role. As a passionate person who is already invested in the IT industry, I will bring commitment, initiative and collaboration to this role.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- MS AZ-900 (Azure Fundamentals)
- MS SC-900 (Security, Compliance and Identity)
- Sophos Certified Engineer
- Datto certified deployment specialist (DCDS)
- Software development by IBM
- Cisco Networking CCNA basic

- Windows server by LinkedIn
- Microsoft Azure by LinkedIn
- Cybersecurity by LinkedIn
- Agile Methodology by LinkedIn
- IT operations by LinkedIn
- EAC Entrepreneur Camp by Indian govt

WORK EXPERIENCE

DEC 2018 - CURRENT

IT AND SECURITY ENGINEER @INTELLECTUAL TECHNOLOGY AND COMMUNICATION

- Working in a team model: Collaborating with colleges to maintain healthy and secure IT infrastructure as a service provider.
- Mentorship and role modelling: Communication, consistency transparency and modelling appropriate behaviors in day-to-day interactions with clients and team. Supporting helpdesk ticket requests along with system generated alerts for Server, Desktop and Network (onprem, hybrid and cloud).
- **Security:** Qualified Sophos certified engineer, specializing in endpoint (ESG), email security and Sophos central, managing over 500 MSP customers for low, mid and high priority alerts.
- **-Network Protection:** Manage Sophos firewall version 15.x,16.x,17.x,18.x and 19.x, creating policy as requested, setting up VPN access for users working from home.
- **Reporting:** Documenting updates/policy with ITglue in professional and accurate manner for better communication. Perform audits and created reports for backup and patch management.
- Monitoring: Monitoring of client's infrastructure according to their SLA, providing client end support for Security and IT related issue afterhours using RMM tools like Continuum, darkwebID, Sophos central, MSP SolarWinds and Splashtop. In addition, provide tech support on live calls, chat and tickets.
- **Ticketing System:** Working closely with team in ConnectWise Manage for smooth ticketing flow and transparency among team.
- **Support client's service plan:** Ensuring I am up to date with each agreement and changes of Infrastructure, resolving critical service and security alerts and managing escalations in IT network operations and security, additionally contributed to achieve 99.99% SLA target availability by delivering high quality services and identifying outages in a proactive manner.
- Backup: Hands on experience with legacy (StorageCraft) and SaaS (Datto) backups.

- -Email Protection: MailGuard and Sophos email protection.
- -Patch Management: Managing windows and macOS security, quality, cumulative and Third-party patches.
- -Knowledgebase Management: Constantly updating KB articles for easy troubleshooting for peers.
- -**Skills:** Windows Server, Computer Maintenance, Active Directory, Technical Support, Troubleshooting, Network Admin, Software Installation, Patch Management, Microsoft 365 (outlook, SharePoint, OneDrive etc.), Security and Backup.
- **-Training:** Continuously attending trainings of products for managing infrastructure and resolve customer problems and leave them extremely satisfied with service received.

JUNE 2016 - NOV 2018

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER @VIBHUTI TECHNOLOGY, BANGALORE

- Initial experience: June 16 to Jan 17 worked as BDE, sourcing international web and mobile app development work via freelancer and upwork
- Promotion: Promoted to BDM after Jan 2017
- Sales: Established sales pipeline by bringing revenue from international clients
- -Method: Adapted agile methodology for better productivity
- -Team: Worked closely with pilot team to ensure expected outcome, managing team of 20
- Reports: Continuously creating reports for optimizing workflow
- Campaigns: Worked closely with SEO consultants for better engagement digitally
- Consulting medium & large enterprise for ERP, CRM, SCM solution, deep understanding of industrial ERP.
- Requirements gathering and cost-estimation after analysis of specific project required resources.
- Proposing quote based on complete requirement gathering for any software system.
- Scrawling SRS documentation as well as delivering presentations for pre-developed products.
- Effective negotiating skills, over the phone, email, and in person.
- Appointment setting via timezest
- Drafted whitepaper campaigns

RELATED SKILLS

- Microsoft 365
- System Administrator
- Network Operations
- Basic cloud knowledge (IaaS)
- Security and Backup
- Basic knowledge of TCP/IP, DNS, DHCP
- Event Viewer

- IT Operations
- Active Directory
- Troubleshooting
- Virtualization
- Strong Communication skills
- Sophos XG Firewall rule review
- Email security

EDUCATIONAL AND TRAINING

• B. TECH (COMPUTER SCIENCE), RK UNIVERSITY
2012 to 2016 (4 years course including 2 internships)
Scored First Class